$(document).ready(function(){

var questionPool = [
	{
		"Question" : "In what phase of the movie's filming timeline did Heath Ledger pass away?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"After the film was completed filming", 
							"Before his role was finished filming", 
							"After the filming in the United States was finished", 
							"2 weeks before the Academy Awards",
						],
		"answer" : "After the filming in the United States was finished"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "Who designed the original concept of the Joker's makeup for the film?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"Christopher Nolan", 
							"Heath Ledger", 
							"Mark Hamill", 
							"DC Comics",
						],
		"answer" : "Heath Ledger"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "In what city is this movie filmed?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"New York", 
							"Boston", 
							"Chicago", 
							"Seattle",
						],
		"answer" : "Chicago"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "While filming the chase scene with the Joker and the SWAT vans..",
		"answerChoices": [
							"One of only four IMAX cameras in the world was destroyed", 
							"Gary Oldman broke a rib", 
							"Christian Bale raged on set", 
							"Christopher Nolan's foot was broken by a lead pipe",
						],
		"answer" : "One of only four IMAX cameras in the world was destroyed"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "Bruce Wayne drives a Lamborghini Murcielago in the movie. The English word for murci√©lago is ..",
		"answerChoices": [
							"Protector", 
							"Bat", 
							"Glider", 
							"Savior",
						],
		"answer" : "Bat"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "This movie takes place how long after Batman Begins?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"8 Months", 
							"2 Years", 
							"3 Weeks", 
							"1 Year",
						],
		"answer" : "8 Months"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "The first four days of scheduled shooting resulted in no film being rolled. Instead, Christopher Nolan screened two films for the cast and crew with a break in between. What was the first film shown?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"Batman Begins", 
							"A Clockwork Orange", 
							"Citizen Kane", 
							"Heat",
						],
		"answer" : "Heat"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "The nine-minute suite composed for the Joker is based on two notes. What two notes comprise the piece?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"D and C for DC comics", 
							"C and B for Christian Bale", 
							"C and A", 
							"E and C",
						],
		"answer" : "D and C for DC comics"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "How many Academy Award nominations did this movie receive?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"3", 
							"5", 
							"6", 
							"8",
						],
		"answer" : "8"
	},
	{
		"Question" : "The Gotham City license plates were directly modeled off of what state's license plates?",
		"answerChoices": [
							"Illinois", 
							"New York", 
							"Arizona", 
							"New Jersey",
						],
		"answer" : "Heat"
	},
];


// Dont forget music! Spotify API for the dark knight?
var totalNumberOfQuestions = 10;
var correctAnswer = 0;
var incorrectAnswer = 0;
var timeAllowed = 95;
var counter ;
var unansweredAmount = 0;
var index = 0;

function reset(){
	correctAnswer = 0;
	incorrectAnswer = 0;
	unansweredQuestions = 0;
	timeAllowed = 95;
	$("#resultsRow").fadeOut(500);
	$("#headerRow").delay(2000).fadeIn(3000);
	clearInterval(counter);
	$('input[type="radio"]:checked').prop('checked', false);
	index = 0;
	$("#questionGroup").empty(); 
};

function run() {
	counter = setInterval(decrement, 1000);

};

function decrement() {
	timeAllowed--;
	$("#timeAllowed").html("<h2>" + timeAllowed + "</h2>");

	if (timeAllowed == 0) {
		solveTheCrime();
	}
};



function displayQuestion(index){

	// This is my object with my questions and answers in it.
	var object = questionPool[index];
	console.log(index);
	// This is creating a variable named question equal to the array value of question for the object variable
	var question = object["Question"];
	// This is creating a variable named choices which is equal to the array value of answer choices within the object
	var choices = object["answerChoices"];
	// This is creating a variable named header equal to the jquery of adding html
	var header = $("<h2>");
	// This is taking <h2> and adding the text from the question variable
	header.text(question);
	// This is dynamically adding the updated header and appending it to the DOM in the #questionGroup id
	$("#questionGroup").prepend(header);


	// This is running a for loop for the answer choices
	for (var i = 0; i < choices.length; i++){
		// Here we are creating a variable named label, and assigning the jquery html value of <label> to it.
		var label = $("<label>");
		// In the label variable that we are going to be dynamically inserting into the html, we are giving it a class of radio-inline and answer, making the buttons that sit next to one another on a row.
		label.addClass("radio-inline answer");
		// Simple console of the label variable, which should have the classes added above now.
		// creating a variable named input that will be creating buttons with.
		var input= $("<input>");
		// Adding data attributes to the input variable of type: "radio"
		input.attr("type", "radio");
		input.attr("value", choices[i]);
		// This is creating all answer choices based on the amount of answers in the array, so for the ones we have now, should create 4 answers each
		label.text(choices[i]);
		// This is actually appending the input variable (answer choices) to the redefined label variable. 
		label.append(input);
		// dynamically adding the information using jquery to the dom using the append method.
		$("#questionGroup").append(label);
		input.attr("name", "optradio");

	};
};

function suitUp(){
	// play music
	run();
	$("#questionsRow").delay(1000).fadeIn(3000);
	$("#questionGroup").delay(1000).fadeIn(3000);
	$("#headerRow").fadeOut(1000);
	displayQuestion(index);
	
};

// Here, I would like to have a function that determines what 
// question we are on by using a for loop to detect the id, 
// so for example, for loop question[i], move on to the next 
// question. This would be inside an event listener for button 
// click of the nextCrimeButton
function nextCrime() {
	
	
	

	var userInput = $("input:checked").val();
	var answer = questionPool[index].answer;

	if (answer == userInput){
		correctAnswer++;
	}

	else {
		incorrectAnswer++;
	}


	index++;
	
	$("#questionGroup").empty(); 
	// console.log(index);
	if (index >= questionPool.length){
		solveTheCrime();
		
	}
	else{
		displayQuestion(index);
	}

	
};


function solveTheCrime(){
	$("#correctAnswerAmount").text(correctAnswer);
		$("#incorrectAnswerAmount").text(incorrectAnswer);
		var totalUnanswered = questionPool.length - (correctAnswer + incorrectAnswer);
		$("#unansweredAmount").text(totalUnanswered);
		$("#questionGroup").hide();
		$("#questionsRow").hide();
		$("#resultsRow").show();
		$("#resultsPage").show();
		console.log("crime solving working")

	};


	$(document).on("click", "#suitUpButton", function(){
		suitUp();
	});


	$(document).on("click", "#resetTheCrimeButton", reset);

	$("#nextCrimeButton").on("click", nextCrime);

});



















